Register of the Alfred Kohlberg papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence and Subject File, 1944-1960 (Boxes 1-207)
  - U.S. News and World Report
    - 1945-1960, 3 folders (Box 193)
  - United States News
  - United World Federalists, Inc.
  - V, miscellaneous
    - 1957-1960
    - 1954-1956
    - 1952-1953
    - to 1951
    - *
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 2 folders
  - Vandercook, John
  - Van Der Vlugt, E.
  - Van Dusen, Henry P.
  - Van Fleet, James A.
  - Van Kleek, Mary
  - Van Passen, Pierre
  - Varga, Bela
  - Vargas, President Getulio
  - Varney, Harold Lord
  - Vassar College
  - Velde, Harold H.
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States
  - Vienna World Youth Festival (Box 194)
  - Vietnam
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison
  - Vinacke, Harold M.
  - Vincent, John Carter
  - Vogeler, Robert
  - Voice of America
  - Von Mises, Ludwig
  - Von Varady
  - Vorys, John M.
  - Voters, U.S.A.
  - W, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1956
    - 1955
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952 (Box 195)
    - 1951
    - 1950
    - *1949-1951
    - 1949
    - 1948
    - 1947
    - 1946
    - ***1944-1948
    - to 1945 December 31
  - Wallace, Henry A., 2 folders (Box 196)
  - Walsh, Pat
  - Walter, Francis
  - Wang Ping-nan
  - Wang Shih-chieh
  - War Department
  - War service, etc., Alfred Kohlberg
  - Warburg, James P.
  - Ward, Angus
  - Ward, Barbara
  - Ward, Harry F.
  - Ward, Stuart R. (Box 197)
  - Warga, Gerzson (Box 198)
  - Warner, William E., 2 folders
  - Washington, George
    - General
    - Farewell address
  - Washington, D.C.
  - Washington, D.C. newspapers
    - Clippings and correspondence
      - 1953-
      - 1949-1952
      - *1949-1954
      - to 1948
    - Washington Post and Times Herald
      - *1955 May
      - to 1954 March, 2 folders
  - Washington Committee, 1953
  - Waters, Agnes
  - Watertown (New York) (Box 199)
  - Watson, Emile E.
  - Watson, Goodwin
  - Watts, Richard
  - Watts, V. Orval
  - Waymack, W. W., Des Moines Register and Tribune, 2 folders
  - We the People
  - Weaver, Phillip
  - Wechsler, James
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1946-1960; 8 folders
  - Wehle, Louis B.
  - Wei, Jimmy, 2 folders
  - Wei Tao-ming
  - Weigle
  - Weir, Ernest T., 2 folders (Box 200)
  - Welch, Herbert
  - Welch, Robert H. W., 1950-1960; 3 folders
  - Welles, Sumner, 2 folders
  - Wellesley College
  - Wells, Charles A.
  - Wells, Kenneth Dale [See: Freedoms Foundation]
  - West, Rebecca
  - West Point, 2 folders
  - Western World Magazine
  - Wetzel, Frank E.
  - Weyl, Nathaniel
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 2 folders
  - Wheeler, George Shaw
  - Wherry, Kenneth S., 2 folders
  - White, C. M.
  - White, Harry Dexter (Box 201)
  - White, Lynn
  - White, Theodore
  - White, Walter
  - White, William L.
  - White Paper on China, 1949
  - Whitehall Letter, 1951
  - Whitehouse, F. W.
  - Whiteside, Edward
  - Whitney, Lloyd and Leila
  - Who's Who
  - Wick, James L.
  - Widener, Alice [See also: U.S.A. Magazine]
  - Wilbur, Brayton
  - Wilbur, C. Martin
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman
  - Wilbur, William H.
  - Wilcox, Edward Barkley
  - Wilcox, Henry
  - Wiley, Alexander, 2 folders
  - Wiley, Charles
  - Willen, Joseph
  - Williams, Herschel
  - Willkie, Wendell, 2 folders
  - Win the Peace Conference, 1946 April (Box 202)
  - Winchell, Walter
  - Winfield, Gerald F.
  - Winnington, Alan
  - Winrod, Gerald F.
  - Winterton, Paul
  - Wisconsin, University of
  - Wise, Jennings C.
  - Wise, Stephen S.
  - Wittfogel, Karl A.
  - Wittmer, Felix, 2 folders
  - Wolfe, Bertram D.
  - Woltman, Frederick, 3 folders
  - Women Investors Research Institute, Inc.
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
  - Wood, Junius B., 2 folders
  - Woodcuts
  - Woodhead, H. G. W.
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, The
  - WOR (New York radio station)
  - World Affairs Center for the United States
  - World Affairs, Dallas Council on
  - World Affairs, Council on
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California
  - World Anti-Communist Congress for Freedom and Liberty
  - World Assembly of Youth
  - World Citizenship Movement
  - World Council of Churches
  - World Federalists [See: United World Federalists]
  - World Federation of Trade Unions
  - World Fellowship of Faiths
  - World Health Organization
  - World Peace Foundation
  - World Report, -1947
  - World Telegram and Sun
    This New York newspaper was previously called The World Telegram.
    - Correspondence and clippings, 1954-1960; 4 folders (Box 203)
    - Clippings
      - 1949 June - 1953, 8 folders
      - 1948 March - 1949 May, 15 folders (Box 204)
      - 1946 May - 1948 February, 21 folders (Box 205)
      - 1945 - 1946 April, 4 folders (Box 206)
  - Wormser, Rene A.
  - Worthy, William
  - Wortis, Joseph
  - Wright, Frederick
  - Wright, Quincey
  - Wriston, Henry M.
  - Wu, K. C.
  - Wyman, Louis C.
  - Wyzanski, Charles E.
  - X, Y, Z, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 207)
  - Yaffe, Richard A.
  - Yakhontoff, Victor
  - Yale University
  - Yalta Papers
  - Yalta Conference
  - Yarnell, Admiral Harry E.
  - Yeh, George K. C.
  - Yoh, Bernard
  - Yonkers
  - Young, James R.
  - Young, Robert E.
  - Young, Stephen M.
  - Young China Publishing Company [See: Shih-chi Wu]
  - Young Democrats of New York
  - Young Women's Christian Associations (Y.W.C.A.)
  - Yu Tsune-chi (James Yu)
  - Yu-pin, Archbishop Paul, 2 folders
  - Yugoslavia
  - Zacharias, Rear Admiral Ellis M.
  - Zarubin, George N.
  - Zellerbach, J. D.
  - Zengler, John
  - Zhukov, Georgi Konstantinovich
  - Zierins, T.
  - Zwicker, General Ralph W.
- Asian Geopolitical File, 1945-1960 (Boxes 208-219)
  Clippings and printed matter relating to political, social, and economic developments, arranged by country/geographic region.
  - Asia
    - Communism (Box 208)
    - Intelligence systems
    - Religious groups
  - Burma
    - Economic, racial, social, educational (Box 209)
    - Foreign relations
    - Government
    - History and geography
    - Military and operational
    - Personalities
    - Newspaper clippings
  - Ceylon
  - China
    - Communications (Box 210)
    - Government
      - Constitution, legislation
      - Political parties
        - General
        - Communism, 2 folders
      - Organization, administration, national leaders
    - Military
      - Organization of army and navy
      - Operations (Box 211)
      - U.S. forces in China
    - Personalities
    - Social
      - Racial and religious
      - Living conditions
        - Labor and sanitation
        - Jimmy Yen's plan for village rehabilitation
      - Cultural, educational, scientific
    - Transportation
    - Clippings, 1949-1954; 5 folders (Box 212)
  - Formosa
    - Government, history, geography, general description (Box 213)
    - Policies, plans for defense, U.S. policy and aid
    - Clippings, 1954
  - Japan
    - Military and operational (Box 214)
    - Social, economic, racial, educational
    - Clippings
  - Korea
    - Communism
    - Economic, social, racial
    - Government
    - History and geography (Box 215)
    - Policy and relations
    - Military and operational
    - Personalities
    - Clippings, 2 folders
    - Clippings, 4 folders (Box 216)
    - Clippings (Box 217)
  - Malaya
    - General
    - Government, history
  - Manchuria
    - Economic, scientific, racial, social, education
    - Government
    - History and geography
    - Military and operational
    - Communism
    - Personalities
    - Policy and foreign relations
    - Clippings
  - Near East and Middle East clippings (Box 218)
  - Egypt, 3 folders
  - India (Box 219)
  - Kashmir
  - Pakistan
- News Releases, 1944-1960 (Boxes 220-221)
  News releases of Alfred Kohlberg, arranged chronologically.
  - News releases by Alfred Kohlberg
    - 1959-1960 (Box 220)
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1956
    - 1955
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952
    - 1951 (Box 221)
    - 1950
    - 1949
    - 1948
    - 1947
    - 1946
    - 1945
    - 1944
  - Miscellaneous news release enclosures, 1938-1951, undated
- Asian Biographical File, 1944-1960 (Boxes 222-229)
  Four ring binders and one card file containing biographical information on notable persons of Southeast Asia and China.
  - Biographies of Asians and Americans who worked in Asia (e.g., John S. Service, John Carter Vincent, General Patrick J. Hurley) in three ring binders (Box 222)
  - Alphabetical index to the biographies (one binder) (Box 223)
  - Alphabetical biography card file (Boxes 224-229)
- Incremental Materials (Boxes 230-237)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1937-2005 (Boxes 238-240)
  - Copy of The China Lobby Man by Joseph Keeley, 1969 (Box-folder 238: 1)
  - Various clippings removed from inside the copy of The China Lobby Man by Joseph Keeley, 1950-1971 (Box-folder 238: 2)
  - Scrapbook and memoir titled "To my Grandchildren," by Alfred Kohlberg, 1958 (Box-folder 238: 3)
  - Copy of the last will and testament of Alfred Kohlberg, 1960 (Box-folder 238: 4)
  - Correspondence from notable persons from file labeled "Celebrity autographs,", 1940-1951 (Box-folder 238: 5)
  - Writings, 1944 (Box-folder 238: 6)
  - Correspondence from Herzstein, Robert E., 2005 (Box-folder 238: 7)
  - "Historical Research Foundation" materials, circa 1950s (Box-folder 238: 8)
  - Genealogical research, 2001 (Box-folder 238: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 238: 10)
  - Photo album, undated (Box 239)
  - Scrapbook and small framed photograph, 1937-1953 (Box 240)